Jay Jansheski · Generalist & Full-Stack Software Engineer

jay@jansheski.com · Seattle, WA · 206-910-3035 · Github · LinkedIn

Summary

Software Engineer and generalist with 15 years experience in designing, programming, deploying, and maintaining bootstrapped web-applications. I do my best to take initiative and ownership of projects and issues, to communicate efficiently, to elevate my colleagues, and to be a good teammate and citizen.

Skills

- Design & Build: Ruby on Rails, Django & Python, AWS, Redis, Postgres, REST APIs, Logistics Workflows
- · Front end: JavaScript, jQuery, VueJS, React. HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS
- Tools: Git & Github, command line, VSCode, etc.
- · Pragmatic, can-do attitude and friendly vibes

Experience

Director of Technology, Garagiste, Seattle, WA · 2020 - Present

- · Sole engineer for an e-commerce and shipping logistics app built with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL & hosted on AWS
- Collaborate across Sales, Acquisition, Shipping & Fulfillment, Customer Service, and Accounting to gather requirements, clarify scope and work with stakeholders to invent and implement solutions to make the organization operate with maximum efficiency
- · Rebuilt the AWS stack to migrate from OpsWorks to a custom deployment solution
- · Rewrote the administrative interface using Rails and VueJS
- Developed inventory modules and created interfaces for managing customer orders, returns, and shipments
- · Created modules that allow customers to manage exchanges, refunds, shipments, and gift certificates
- · Implemented a caching system to improve page-load times and site performance
- Manage third-party vendors on both technical and marketing-related projects

Lead Software Engineer, Index Newspapers (The Stranger), Seattle, WA · 2008 - 2020

- Led a team of 4 engineers to develop and maintain the editorial sites of the Stranger and the Portland Mercury (thestranger.com, portlandmercury.com)
- Built e-commerce sites Bold Type Tickets and AltPerks (boldtypetickets.com, strangertickets.com) using a proprietary web framework written on top of Perl and MySQL
- Re-wrote significant parts of the stack in Python & Django (everout.com)
- Worked with the team to invent and develop all aspects of the online purchase process, but considerable effort also
 went into developing the administrative portion of the site where venue owners enter events, tickets, and view reports
 about their sales and account status
- Managed development of the API and companion iOS ticket-scanning app which allowed mobile devices to work as scanners at large-scale events like Seattle's Capitol Hill Block Party and Bumbershoot

VP of Technology, Americas Generators, Miami FL · 2003 - 2008

- Built the website (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP) and the network (Windows Server 2000)
- Oversaw implementation of our ERP system SX.enterprise and developed an integrated intranet order tracking system
- · Handled web marketing and site content including a catalog of a thousand products
- Designed print ads, brochures, and multimedia presentations; wrote copy, spec sheets, and photographed products
- Handled help desk issues for a 40+ person operation
- Purchased and oversaw implementation of an Avaya phone system
- Handled accounting and inventory issues
- Acted as liaison to G.E. Finance and managed monthly floor-planning audits and created procedures and workflow guidelines for sales, service, and shipping & receiving

Education & Hobbies

- University of Florida, Gainesville FL, Bachelor of Fine Arts in Drawing. Graduated with Highest Honors.
- Hobbies include hiking, cycling, writing, and drawing. Completed the *Miami Marathon* and the *Seattle to Portland* and *Seattle to Vancouver* bike rides. Summited Rainier in 2016.